<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Org on Aatmun Baxi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Org on Aatmun Baxi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Emacs org-mode for LaTeX</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/computing/emacs-to-type-latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/computing/emacs-to-type-latex/</guid>
      <description>About four years ago, my brother introduced me to Linux and free and open source software. Around the same time I learned to use LaTeX to typeset documents with lots of mathematical notation. I then stumbled across Gilles Castel’s article on typing LaTeX with vim, and I was amazed.&#xA;For those who don’t know, typing LaTeX by default is a terrible experience. Terrible. Using a program like vim with plugins made typing LaTeX so frictionless that I immediately dove into the world of extensible text editors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emacs org-mode for LaTeX</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/comp/emacs-to-type-latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/comp/emacs-to-type-latex/</guid>
      <description>About four years ago, my brother introduced me to Linux and free and open source software. Around the same time I learned to use LaTeX to typeset documents with lots of mathematical notation. I then stumbled across Gilles Castel’s article on typing LaTeX with vim, and I was amazed.&#xA;For those who don’t know, typing LaTeX by default is a terrible experience. Terrible. Using a program like vim with plugins made typing LaTeX so frictionless that I immediately dove into the world of extensible text editors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My DOOM Emacs Configuration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/computing/doom-config/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/computing/doom-config/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents Intro Housekeeping Font Theme, Appearance, General Behavior Doom Dashboard Modeline Global Appearance Custom Faces Custom Functionality Global keybindings Major Modes and Languages org-mode haskell-mode python-mode plantuml pdf-view-mode evil lsp numpydoc Packages bibtex embark org packages org-ref org-roam org-noter org-super-agenda CV Misc Packages and Behavior helm-bibtex xenops-mode yasnippets ink quiver company Intro This config file is organized by mode and/or package. Each mode has their own subsection for common configuration patterns such as keybindings, hooks, setting variables, etc.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
