<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Categories on Aatmun Baxi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/categories/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Categories on Aatmun Baxi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/categories/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Realizing some Multiplicity-Free Fusion Rules</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/realizing_fusion_rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/realizing_fusion_rules/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: These results have not been subjected to the rigors of publication.&#xA;Fusion Rings Classifying fusion categories is a huge task&amp;ndash;likely impossible&amp;ndash;but much effort has been made to find certain invariants to help distinguish fusion categories at various levels of structure. One such invariant is the fusion ring associated to a fusion category \( \mathcal{C} \). They are one of the more useful invariants of fusion categories, though they are incomplete at determining the whole structure of the category.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Computing, Braids, and Modular Categories</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/math/quantum_comp_and_modular_categories/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/math/quantum_comp_and_modular_categories/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Quantum computing (QC) is an exciting new paradigm of computation, promising exponential speedup from state-of-the-art classical algorithms in certain computing tasks. Despite vigorous research from all sides of the task, obstacles to a quantum computer architecture that is scalable and tolerant to errors remain hard to overcome.&#xA;Qubits in existing models of quantum computation (such as trapped-ion models) are sensitive to their environment. Such sensitivities of the environment make qubits liable to introducing noise that dominates the computation we’d like to measure.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
